Guide to the Maurice F. Neufeld papers, ca. 1941-1949
Neufeld, Maurice F. papers, ca. 1941-1949
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Maurice F. Neufeld papers, ca. 1941-1949.
4002
Maurice F. Neufeld
3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notebooks, pamphlets, and bulletins.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, notebooks, pamphlets, and bulletins concerning Maurice F. Neufeld's association with New York State government work during World War II, 1941-1943, and in 1948-1949.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Maurice F. Neufeld is a Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, notebooks, pamphlets, and bulletins concerning Maurice F. Neufeld's association with New York State government work during World War II, 1941-1943, and in 1948-1949.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Neufeld, Maurice F.
Subjects:
World War, 1939-1945.; College teachers.
Places:
New York (State)--Politics and government.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- New York State--Central Statistical Committee
  - Central Statistical Committee--New York (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Central Statistical Committee--Other states (Box 1, Folder 2)
- New York State--Commerce Division
  - Commerce Division--Activities--Reports (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Commerce Division--Business and Defense Report (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Commerce Division--Clippings (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Commerce Division--Industry--Productive Capacity--NY (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Commerce Division--Subcontracting--NY (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Commerce Division--Library (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Commerce Division--Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Commerce Division--Taxation--Other States (Box 1, Folder 10)
- New York State--Planning Division
  - Planning Division--Maps and Mapping (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Planning Division--Maps (notebook) (Box 1)
  - Planning Division--Manual of Information and Office Procedure--Vol. I (notebook) (Box 1)
  - Planning Division--Planning Division--Manual of Information and Office Procedure--Vol. II (notebook) (Box 1)
  - Planning Division--State--New York (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Planning Division--State--Other States (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Planning Division--Transportation--Highways--Protection and Development--NY (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Planning Division--Transportation--Motor Vehicle Commission--NY (Box 1, Folder 15)
- New York State--Post-War Problems
  - Post-War Problems (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Post-War Problems--Federal Works Reserve--Clippings (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Post-War Problems--Local--New York (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Employment Committee (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Employment Committee, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Employment Committee, June-Dec. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Employment Committee, Jan.-June 1942 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Employment Committee--Clippings (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Employment Committee--Letters (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Public Works Planning Commission (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Public Works Planning Commission--Clippings (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Post-War Problems--NY--Post-War Public Works Planning Commission--Maps (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Post-War Problems--Public Works Program--New York (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Post-War Problems--Public Works Program--United States (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Post-War Problems--Public Works Program--Public Works Reserve--NY (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Post-War Problems--Public Works Program--Public Works Reserve--Other States (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Post-War Problems--Public Works Program--Public Works Reserve--U.S. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Post-War Problems--Other States and Countries (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Post-War Problems--United States--Other Countries--Clippings (Box 1, Folder 34)
- New York State--Rationing Division
  - NYS-Rationing Division--Chairmen (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - NYS-Rationing Division--Personnel (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - NYS-Rationing Division--Office Procedures--Apr. 22, 1942 (notebook) (Box 2)
  - NYS-Rationing Division--Office Procedures (notebook) (Box 2)
  - NYS-Rationing Division--Office Procedures and Forms (notebook) (Box 2)
  - Memorandum to Hamm & Bane (3 blue binders) (Box 2)
  - NYS--Rationing Division--Rationing (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - NYS--Rationing Division--Rationing--July 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NYS--Rationing Division--Rationing--Aug. 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NYS--Rationing Division--Rationing--Sept. 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - NYS--Rationing Division--Rationing--Reports (pamphlet box)
    - U.S. Office of Price Administration. Emergency Gasoline Rationing Regulations. Ration Order No. 5. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1942. (Form O.P.A.R--519) (Box 2)
    - U.S. Office of Price Administration. Emergency Plan for Gasoline Rationing. Official Information and Instructions for Those Who Will Carry Out the Plan. Washington: GPO, 1942. (Form OPA R-517) (Box 2)
    - N.Y.S. Bureau of Rationing, Maurice F. Neufeld, Director. Bulletin No. 57. Subject: Gasoline Rationing, April 28, 1942. (Box 2)
    - U.S. Office of Price Administration. Sugar Rationing Regulations. Rationing Order No. 3. Washington, D.C.: GPO, 1942. (O.P.A. Form R-313) (Box 2)
    - U.S. Office of Price Administration. The Plan for Distributing War Ration Book One for Individual Consumers. Official Information and Instructions for Those Who Will Carry Out the Plan. Washington, D.C.: GPO, 1942. (OPA Form No. R-308, Revised Mar. 25, 1942) (Box 2)
    - U.S. Office of Price Administration, Sugar Rationing. The Plan for Trade Registration. Registration of Retailers, Wholesalers, Institutions, and Industrial Users, Including Food Service Establishments. Washington, D.C.: GPO, 1942. (O.P.A. Form No. R-312) (Box 2)
    - U.S. Office of Price Administration. Rationing Order No. 3--Sugar Rationing Regulations. Advance Proof for Use of Field Offices and Local Rationing Boards. Washington, D.C.: GPO, 1942. (Box 2)
    - U.S. Office of Price Administration, Office for Emergency Management. New Passenger Automobile Rationing Regulations, Order No. 2A, Effective March 2, 1942, Establishing Provisions and Procedures for Rationing New Passenger Automobiles. Washington, D.C.: GPO, [1942]. (Box 2)
    - U.S. Office of Price Administration, Office for Emergency Management. Tire Rationing Regulations (Revised), Establishing a Program for Rationing Tires and Tubes, Retreading and Recapping of Tires, and Camelback, February 19, 1942. These Regulations Supersede Tire Rationing Regulations Issued on December 30, 1941, by the Office of Price Administration. Washington, D.C.: GPO, 1942. (Box 2)
    - N.Y.S. Bureau of Rationing. Report, New York State Bureau of Rationing, December 22, 1941-May 16, 1942, to the New York State War Council. June 1942. (3 copies) (Box 2)
- Office of Price Administration
  - Office of Price Administration--Rent Control-Office Procedures (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Office of Price Administration--Rent Control--Manual of Internal Procedures (1 black binder) (Box 2)
- New York State--War Council
  - The Empire State at War: World War II. Compiled and written for the New York State War Council by Karl Drew Hartzell, Ph.D. Published by the State of New York, 1949. (Book) (Box 3)
  - Pamphlet box which contains the following:
    - State of New York. Manual for Local Defense Councils. NYS Council of Defense, 1941. (3 copies) (Box 3)
    - State of New York. New York State and Local Defense Programs. Reprint of Addresses at Annual Meeting of the Association of Towns, Chancellors Hall, Albany, February, 1941. Prepared by the New York State Defense Council, State Capitol, Albany, N.Y. (Box 3)
    - State of New York. New York State at War. Second Annual Report, New York State War Council, 1942. Albany, N.Y.: New York State War Council, 1942. (Box 3)
    - State of New York. Message of the Governor Recommending Defense Legislation. Albany: Williams Press, Inc., 1942. Legislative Document (1942), No. 27. (5 copies) (Box 3)
    - State of New York. Message of Governor Herbert H. Lehman to the Legislature, January 7, 1942. For Release Upon Delivery, Wednesday, Jan. 7, 1942, and Not to be Previously Published or Quoted From or Used in Any Manner, Walter T. Brown, Secretary to the Governor. (4 copies) (Box 3)
    - State of New York, Department of Correction. The Individual in a Democracy at War. A Social Studies Course Designed to Bring About Individual Intelligent Action for the United States in Winning the War and the Peace. Albany, N.Y.: Division of Education, June 1, 1942. (Box 3)
    - New York State War Council, Office of War Training Programs. Instructor-Training Manual. A Suggested Course in General Teaching Methods to be Used in Training Instructors Who Will Teach Civilian War Training Courses Sponsored by the New York State and Local War Councils. Prepared by the State Office of War Training Programs at the Request of the State War Plans Coordinator, Sept. 15, 1942. (Box 3)
    - Peabody, May E. Parents Prepare: Maintaining Family Morale in Wartime. Albany: New York State Council of Defense and New York State Education Department, 1942. Education for Civilian Defense Bulletin 3. (4 copies) (Box 3)
    - New York State. Report on New York State Defense Program including Governor Herbert H. Lehman's Message of Transmittal to the Legislature [Aug, 1, 1940-Dec. 1, 1941]. New York State Council of Defense, Governor Herbert H. Lehman, Chairman. (Box 3)
    - A "Business" Program to Finance Military Victory Now and Economic Victory after the War. Clinton Davidson, Jr., Economist, Fiduciary Counsel, Inc., no date [1942?], 29 pp. mimeo. (Box 3)
    - New York State. War Traffic Conservation Plan. 1942. 20 pp. mimeo. (Box 3)
    - New York State Council of Defense, Major General John F. O'Ryan, Director: Bulletin No. 1, July 12, 1941; Bulletin No. 2, July 28, 1941; Bulletin No. 3 (Charts A and B--Organization and Functions), no date; Bulletin No. 4 (Duties and Training of Air Raid Wardens), Sept. 12, 1941. (Box 3)
    - State of New York, Executive Department, Division of Commerce, State Office Building, Albany, New York. Defense Procurement Agencies of the United States Government, no date, 4 pp., mimeo. (Box 3)
    - Supplement "A" to the Report of the Mayor's Capital Improvement Program Committee to the Mayor of the City of Detroit, Edward J. Jeffries, Jr. A Capital Improvement Program Covering Six Years and Reserve, 1942 to 1948. Jan. 1942. 4 pp. mimeo. (Box 3)
    - Mobilizing Schools for Civilian Defense. Albany: University of the State of New York, State Education Department, 1941. (Box 3)
    - New York State Council of Defense. Aircraft Warning Service, no date. (Box 3)
    - New York State Council of Defense. Organization of Auxiliary Fire Corps. 1941. (Box 3)
    - New York State Council of Defense. Organization of Auxiliary Police Corps. 1941. (Box 3)
    - New York State Council of Defense. Recommended Program for Gasoline Conservation. No date. (Box 3)
    - New York State Defense Council. Organization and Training of Civilian Auxiliary Fire Fighting Forces. 1941. Civilian Defense Fire Series Bulletin No. 1. (Box 3)
    - New York State Defense Council. Industrial Fire Prevention and Protection. 1941. Civilian Defense Fire Series Bulletin No. 2. (Box 3)
    - New York State War Council, War Transportation Committee. New York State War Transportation Manual. 1942. (Box 3)
    - New York State War Council, Office of Civilian Mobilization. Fighting the War at Home. Complete Series of 10 Discussion Outlines for Group Leaders: (Box 3)
      - Group Leaders Instructions
      - Blacking Out For Safety, No. 1
      - Fighting Fire Bombs, No. 2
      - Caring for Casualties, No. 3
      - Salvaging for Victory, No. 4
      - Eating for Health, No. 5
      - Stretching Our Supplies, No. 6
      - Freeing Our Children From Fear, No. 7
      - Guarding Our Energies, No. 8
      - Sticking To Facts, No. 9
      - Budgeting To Win, No. 10
  - State of New York. Executive Department. Division of Commerce. Handbook of War Agencies. Albany, Sept. 1942. Publication No. 4. (Box 3)
  - New York State War Council. New York State War Emergency Act and Other War Emergency Laws, 1941 and 1942. Compiled and Published by New York State War Council Pursuant to the Provisions of Chapter 573 of the Laws of 1942. June 15, 1942. (Box 3)
  - New York State War Coucil. Official Bulletin, Vol. I, No. 3, Aug. 8, 1942. (22 copies) (Box 3)
  - New York State War Council. Official Bulletin, Vol. I, No. 23, Dec. 19, 1942; Vol. I, No. 24, Dec. 26, 1942; Vol. II, No. 2, Jan. 9, 1943; Vol. II, No. 3, Jan. 16, 1943; Vol. II, No. 4, Jan. 16, 1943 (Index to the Official Bulletin), 2 copies; Vol. II, No. 4, Jan. 23, 1943; Vol. II, No. 5, Jan. 30, 1943; Vol. II, No. 6, Feb. 6, 1943; Vol. II, No. 7, Feb. 13, 1943; Vol. II, No. 8, Feb. 20, 1943; Vol. II, No. 9, Feb. 27, 1943; Vol. II, No. 10, Mar. 6, 1943; Vol. II, No. 11, Mar. 13, 1943; Vol. II, No. 12, Mar. 20, 1943; Vol. II, No. 13, Mar. 27, 1943; Vol. II, No. 14, Apr. 3, 1943; Vol. II, No. 16, Apr. 17, 1943 (Box 3)
  - War Council--Social and Economic Survey--Local--NY (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - War Council--Training Programs (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Quartermaster Depot--Philadelphia
  - Quartermaster Depot--Philadelphia--Employee Relations (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Quartermaster Depot--Philadelphia--Office Procedures (Box 3, Folder 4)